Software Development Engineer

I'm a full-time student at UC Berkeley. Major in Computer Science and Data Science. Expected Graduation Year is May 2023.

Driven by the development of technology, I have a strong interest in artificial intelligence and computer science. I changed my career to become a programmer. Before that, I'm an Advertising Project Manager with 10+ years of experience with global advertising firms. Expert in data analysis, time management, budget management, problem-solving, etc.



415-629-7620



xiayushan@berkeley.edu



https://github.com/tigerisbigcat



https://www.linkedin.com/in/lei-hao

Education

De Anza College - Computer Science && Math - GPA 4.0

UC Berkeley - Computer Science && Data Science - Current GPA 3.7

61A: The Structure And Interpretation Of Computer Programs 61B: Data Structures 61C: Computer Architecture 161: Computer Security 186: Database Systems Data144: Data Mining CS70: Discrete Mathematics And Probability Theory

In Progress: · Machine Learning · Artificial Intelligence · Software Engineering ·Mobile Application Design & Development ·Foundations of Computer Graphics ·User Interface Design and Development ·Operating Systems

Working Experience

----- May 2022 - Current

Google SPS Program Participant, Google (U.S.)

- ·Software Product Sprint (SPS) introduction click: here
- ·Build a personally meaningful web app.
- ·Practice interviewing with Google engineers.
- ·Get feedback on your resume from Google recruiters.
- ·Participate in an online community and regularly scheduled career workshops.

November 2018 - July 2019

Marketing Specialist, Huawei Device USA (U.S.)

- ·Optimize the PPC campaign on Amazon.
- ·Distribute marketing materials on social media channels.
- ·Process management. Huawei has its own system to process marketing budgets.
- ·Huawei device product management.

November 2012 - January 2017



Responsible for tutoring drop-in students with their assignments· Guiding my individual session students through their course-

Explain CIS concepts to students. Completed the whole process of

reviewing an assignment, analyzing problems, debug within half hour-

September 2020 - July 2021 •-----

De Anza College Math && CIS Tutor(U.S.)

Build connections with Chinese media, establish good working relationships Published PR articles with their help-Develop media plan, strategy, and budget·

Improved my communication skills, and enhanced my code debugging ability-

Tracking media results. Assemble a comprehensive summary, provide final reports. Tracked about 100 concurrent advertising channels and managed their cash flow-Created a timeline, make sure all the projects complete on time-

------ January 2008 - September 2012

Project Manager, Beijing Emar Online Techology CO., LTD CubeAD Techology CO., LTD (Beijing, China)

- ·Contract Management: Manage project effectiveness and customer expectations
- ·Progress Management: Tracking all the progress details.
- ·Customer Management: Follow the contracts, organize cash flow.
- ·Accounting: Calculate the profits for sales team, KPI, Bonus, etc.

School Projects

The Enigma(WWII German Cipher Machine)



the Enigma machines that Germany used during World War II to encrypt its military communications. More details: https://inst.eecs.berkeley.edu/~cs61b/ fa21/materials/proj/proj1/index.html

Jump-Board Game

Board game. Allowing a user to play against a computer.

More details: https://inst.eecs.berkeley ~cs61b/fa21/materials/proj/proj2/index.html

Use Java to implement a database, including B+ tree, Joins and Query Optimization, Concurrency, Recovery.

More details: https://cs186.gitbook.io/project

Class Spot Monitoring



A program for school class available spot monitoring. notify and register the class if space is available.



Sales Prediction

Trained data, give the 1-2 month ahead sales prediction.



ROI Monitoring

Implement a Database

A BI system for monitoring the Ad's trend in real-time.

Personal Skills

Side Projects











Published Books

Published three fiction books in China in my early 20s. Written By Chinese.